Finding Aid for Guy H. Jenkins papers, 1931-1957
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Guy H. Jenkins papers 1931-1957
Jenkins, Guy Hugh.
1 linear foot and 1 oversize item
851583 Aa 2; Ac
Chief of the Lansing bureau of Booth Newspapers, Inc. Correspondence and other materials concerning his newspaper career and his interest in Michigan politics (particularly the election of 1932) and Michigan politicians Frank Murphy and Blair Moody.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection came from Mrs. Guy H. Jenkins (donor no. 3322 ) and from Herbert G. Watkins (donor no. 2482 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Guy Hugh Jenkins was born April 13, 1888 in Saginaw, Michigan. After graduation from high school in 1907, he went to work the following year as a reporter for the associated Booth newspapers. He came to Lansing in 1927 to assist the bureau in coverage of state government. In 1930, he was selected Chief of the Lansing Bureau. He died May 4, 1957.
The Jenkins collection consists of correspondence dating from 1931 to 1957, various subject files pertaining to issues of state government, and files of his expense accounts. Some of the individuals with whom Jenkins had correspondence included William A. Comstock, James A. Farley, John A. Hannah, Howard C. Lawrence, Frank Murphy, and Frank A. Picard.
Subjects:
Booth Newspapers, Inc.; Elections--Michigan--1932.; Journalists--Michigan--Lansing.; Lansing (Mich.); Michigan--Politics and government--1929-1938.; Moody, Blair, 1902-1954.; American newspapers--Michigan.; Jenkins, Guy H.; Michigan--Politics and government--1837-1950.
Contributors:
Comstock, William Alfred, 1877-1949.; Farley, James A. (James Aloysius), 1888-1976.; Hannah, John A., 1902-; Lawrence, Howard Cyrus, 1890-1961.; Murphy, Frank, 1890-1949.; Picard, Frank A., 1889-1963.
- Correspondence
  - 1931 (Box 1)
  - 1932 (Box 1)
  - 1933-1935 (Box 1)
  - 1936 (Box 1)
  - January-June 1937 (Box 1)
  - July-December 1937 (Box 1)
  - January-April 1938 (Box 1)
  - May-December 1938 (Box 1)
  - January-June 1939 (Box 1)
  - July-December 1939 (Box 1)
  - January-April 1940 (Box 1)
  - May-December 1940 (Box 1)
  - Jan-June 1941 (Box 1)
  - July-December 1941 (Box 1)
  - 1942 (Box 1)
  - 1943 (Box 1)
  - 1944-1945 (Box 1)
  - 1946 (Box 1)
  - 1947 (Box 1)
  - 1948 (Box 1)
  - 1949 (Box 1)
  - 1950-1953 (Box 1)
  - 1954-1957 (Box 1)
- Subject files
  - Consumers Power Company, 1937-1939 (Box 1)
  - Ingham County Grand Jury, 1946-1952 (Box 1)
  - Jenkins honorary degree from the University of Michigan, 1951 (Box 1)
  - Bills passed by the Michigan legislature, 1939 (Box 1)
  - Michigan correctional institutions and prison riots, 1947-1952 (Box 1)
  - Michigan Bell Telephone Company, 1931-1936 (Box 1)
  - Michigan Liquor Control Commission, 1938-1940 (Box 1)
  - Frank Murphy, 1936-1942 (Box 1)
  - Blair Moody, 1951 (Box 1)
- Expense Accounts
  - 1935-1936 (Box 1)
  - 1937-1938 (Box 1)
  - 1939-1940 (Box 1)
  - 1941-1942 (Box 1)
  - 1943-1944 (Box 1)
  - 1945-1948 (Box 1)
  - 1949-1952 (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous
  - Miscellanea, 1870-1948 (Box 1)
  - Resolution of the Michigan State Senate commending Jenkins, 1951 (Folder 1)
Selective Index to Correspondents
Comstock, William Alfred, 1877-1949.
Aug. 20 and 21, 1935, Aug. 28, 1937
Farley, James A. (James Aloysius), 1888-1976.
July 30, 1940 and Sept. 20, 1940
Hannah, John A., 1902-
Nov. 3, 1942, Dec. 21, 1942, Apr. 28, 1945, Feb. 21, 1950 and June 7, 1955
Lawrence, Howard Cyrus, 1890-1961.
1937, Oct. 7, 1938, Dec. 23, 1938, Aug. 11, 1939, Mar. 25, 1940, Apr. 1, 1940, May 14, 1940
Murphy, Frank, 1890-1949.
1936, Oct. 27, 1937, Nov. 9, 1938, 1939, Jan. 8, 1940, May 20, 1940, Aug. 25, 1941, Sept. 5, 1941 and Jan. 26, 1942
Picard, Frank A., 1889-1963.
Oct. 9, 1936, 1937, 1938, Jan. 28, 1939, Mar. 16, 1939, Aug. 25, 1939, Mar. 13, 1941, Apr. 21, 1942, Dec. 14, 1942, Jan. 20, 1943, Mar. 21, 1947